A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries xFA118
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Fahs, Charles B.
  - Trip to California, 1956 October 17-December 13 (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 832)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours Stanford University and UCLA.
    Education; Humanities; Diaries; Music; Art; Religion; Libraries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to Mexico - Index, 1956 December 8-18 (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 904)
    Index; Trip to Mexico; 2 pages.
    Education; Mexico; Humanities; indexes (reference sources); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to Mexico, 1956 December 8-18 (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 906)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to Mexico and gets updated on the contemporary Mexican history project, the Mexican Writing Center and Colegio de Mexico.
    Mexico; Libraries; Dance; Diaries; Humanities; Education; Creative writing; Translations; History; Theater; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1956 December 19-1957 April 5 (Box 143, Reel M Fah 5, Frame 927)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours Howard University and surveys their African studies program, and visits UCLA to review their English language education program.
    East Asia; Philosophy and religion; Theater; Africa; History; Linguistics; Diaries; Education; Religion; United States; Humanities; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to the Far East - Index, 1957 April 15-June 28 (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 1, Box 143)
    Education; Humanities; East Asia; indexes (reference sources); Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - Trip to the Far East, 1957 April 15-June 28 (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 12, Box 143)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours the Far East to focus on RF projects in intercultural studies and the arts.
    Music; Religion; Libraries; Diaries; Architecture; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Art; Drama; Indonesia; Singapore; Taiwan; Japan; Bali; Thailand; Lebanon; Humanities; Education; History; Philosophy and religion; Linguistics; City planning; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1957 July 1-October 11 (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 213, Box 144)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs travels to North Carolina and New England to survey dramatic and performing arts. He attends the U.S. National Commission for UNESCO meeting of Advisory Group on project on Mutual Appreciation of East-West Cultural Values.
    Humanities; Education; United States; Dance; Drama; History; Diaries; Art; Performing arts; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to Europe, 1957 October 12-19 (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 341, Box 144)
    In this brief diary Fahs takes a trip to Europe and tours University of Fribourg, Free University and International Institute for Social History. The emphasis of RF interest in these institutions focuses on ethics and one political and social philosophy.
    Philosophy and religion; Social sciences; Political science; Netherlands; Switzerland; Germany; Slavic studies; Libraries; Diaries; Education; Humanities; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1957 October 22-November 7 (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 362, Box 144)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs travels to North Carolina and New England to survey dramatic and performing arts.
    United States; Education; Humanities; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to the West Coast, 1957 November 7-15 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 389)
    Fahs travels to the West Coast to survey RF interest programs such as English language education, Stanford University Seminar for Business Administrators of Japanese Universities and to attend a UNESCO conference.
    Ethics; Music; Humanities; East Asia; United States; Education; Art; Religion; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1957 November 18-December 31 (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 412, Box 144)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs attends Program of Advanced Religious Studies at Union Theological Seminary, meeting in Washington of the Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on the Third Major Project. He travels to Gambier, Ohio.
    Humanities; United States; Theater; Diaries; Performing arts; Translations; Religion; Art; Education; Dance; Prints; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1958 January 2-April 1 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 485)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes trips to the Southwest, Washington D.C. and Cornell University.
    Dance; Native Americans; Anthropology; Music; United States; Diaries; Humanities; Education; East Asia; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - Trip to Korea - Index, 1958 April 4-May 5 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 653)
    Index; Trip to Japan and Korea; 8 pages.
    Japan; Korea; indexes (reference sources); Humanities; Education; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - Trip to Korea, 1958 April 4-May 5 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 661)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours Korean and Japanese Universities to survey RF intercultural humanities projects that focus on history, philosophy and American studies. During his time in Korea the Korean dictionary and Encyclopedia of Science are discussed.
    History; Libraries; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Diaries; Art; Music; City planning; Education; Japan; Korea; Religion; Humanities; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1958 May 6-August 22 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 744)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs discusses Asian, Arabic and Russian studies.
    United States; Libraries; Theater; Language and languages; Education; Diaries; Humanities; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - Trip to Southeast Asia - Index, 1958 August 24-September 29 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 864)
    Index; Trip to Southeast Asia; 5 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Education; Humanities; Southeast Asia; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - Trip to Southeast Asia, 1958 August 24-September 29 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 869)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to the Southeast to survey RF funded intercultural projects such as language studies. Music and theater are also discussed in the diary.
    Theater; Language and languages; Music; Humanities; Education; Philippines; Indonesia; Diaries; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1958 September 26-December 31 (Box 144, Reel M Fah 6, Frame 933)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to Hebrew Union College and University of California at Berkeley.
    United States; Music; Art; Language and languages; Linguistics; Diaries; Prints; Religion; Humanities; Education; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1959 January 2-April 2 (Reel M Fah 6, Frame 1,085, Box 145)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs visits Harvard, McGill, Yale, Drew, and Westminster Choir College.
    Humanities; United States; Libraries; Education; Archaeology; Music; Diaries; Anthropology; Dance; Economics; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1959 April 4-October 9 (Box 145, Reel M Fah 7, Frame 1)
  - Trip to Canada, Japan, and Okinawa - Index, 1959 April 4-May 2 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 5, Box 145)
    Index; Trip to Canada, Japan and Okinawa; 6 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Canada; Humanities; Japan; Education; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to Canada, Japan, and Okinawa, 1959 April 4-May 2 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 7, Box 145)
    Fahs tours various Universities in Japan and Canada.
    Japan; Diaries; Humanities; Canada; Education; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1959 May 4-October 9 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 77, Box 145)
    Fahs visits the American Symphony Orchestra League and the Twelfth American Dance Festival. He attends the Conference on English Language Teaching in Egypt and the Soviet-Asian Relations Conference. He also surveys an electronic music project at Columbia University.
    United States; Humanities; Education; Dance; Music; Art; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Language and languages; Linguistics; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to England - Index, 1959 October 11-21 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 247, Box 145)
    Index; Trip to England; 3 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); England; Humanities; Education; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to England, 1959 October 11-21 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 250, Box 145)
    Fahs travels to England and tours Oxford, Cambridge and London for RF Humanities grant programs.
    Language and languages; Linguistics; History; Diaries; England; Humanities; Education; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1959 October 22-December 31 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 307, Box 145)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs attends the ACLS Conference on Scholarly Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences, Meeting of the Third Major Project Committee of the US National Commission for UNESCO and Conference on North African Problems. He also plans for his trip to the Middle East.
    United States; Dance; City planning; Education; Humanities; Middle East; Libraries; Music; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to the Middle East - Index, 1960 January 9-24 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 404, Box 145)
    Athens, Beirut, Cairo.
    Index; Trip to Middle East (Athens, Beirut, Cairo); 3 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Greece; Education; Humanities; Lebanon; Egypt; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to the Middle East, 1960 January 9-24 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 407, Box 145)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs travels to the Middle East, Chicago and Appleton-Neeah, Wisconsin. The New York City Center of Music and Drama, Inc.'s Kabuki Drama program is discussed as well.
    Lebanon; United States; Greece; Egypt; Education; Language and languages; Italy; Humanities; Kabuki; Middle East; East Asia; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to Japan and Korea- Index, 1960 April 8-May 7 (Box 146, Reel M Fah 7, Frame 528)
    Index; Trip to Japan and Korea; 3 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Japan; Education; Korea; Humanities; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to Japan and Korea, 1960 April 8-May 7 (Box 146, Reel M Fah 7, Frame 534)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs travels to Japan and Korea. He tours their universities and libraries and assesses their humanities programs. The Stanford Seminar is discussed.
    Universities and colleges; Education; Philosophy and religion; Korea; Humanities; Diaries; Libraries; Japan; Writing; Drama; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1960 May 9-June 30 (Box 146, Reel M Fah 7, Frame 613)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs tours Dartmouth College.
    Education; Philosophy and religion; United States; Humanities; Language and languages; East Asia; Music; Diaries; Linguistics; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1960 July 1-September 30 (Box 146, Reel M Fah 7, Frame 728)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to Interlochen, Michigan, Seattle and Tanglewood, Massachusetts to survey National Music Camp, Sino-American Conference on Intellectual Cooperation and Berkshire Music Center, respectively.
    East Asia; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Music; Education; Diaries; Humanities; United States; Religion; Language and languages; Linguistics; Dance; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1960 October 4-December 9 (Box 146, Reel M Fah 7, Frame 852)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs attends Conference on Coordination and Evaluation of Graduate Foreign Language and Area Fellowship Programs (NDEA) and the Ballet Society Conference.
    Humanities; United States; History; Language and languages; Linguistics; Education; Drama; Religion; Dance; Art; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - Trip to the Middle East, 1960 December 8-20 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 946, Box 146)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Fahs discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of humanities. He is involved in the progress of Humanities Division programs, selection of fellows and grant in-aid, and development of new research. The aims of the Humanities Division are to identify and stimulate new cultural growth, assist in interpretative studies of recent history, assist in American studies in other countries, fund creative writing and initiate major grants in music and other arts. Fahs takes a trip to the Middle East.
    Art; Philosophy and religion; History; Diaries; Translations; Libraries; Iraq; Greece; Linguistics; Language and languages; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Fahs, Charles B. (Charles Burton)
  - 1960 December 22-1961 April 7 (Reel M Fah 7, Frame 971, Box 146)